# SANGEON YONG

 $+82\ 10-5002-4924 \diamond \text{Republic of Korea}$ 

 $sangeon.yong@audai.co \diamond seyong92.github.io$ 

Machine learning engineer and full-stack developer with over 8 years of research experience in signal processing/machine learning. Main research interests are speech and singing voice for analysis and synthesis. Proven success in developing several user applications based on audio technologies.

As an engineer, totally interested in the full product development process that improves user experience with cutting-edge technologies, from back-end and system to front-end and UI/UX. Also, as an early adopter, very active in introducing new technologies and products into projects and teams.

As a coder, absorbed in automation and code readability, which improves working and cooperation efficiency.

## CORE SKILLS

- Machine learning and signal processing: Python (PyTorch, BentoML), MATLAB
- Front-end: JavaScript/TypeScript (React, SolidJS, Web Audio API), HTML/CSS
- Back-end: Python (FastAPI)

(Topic: Real-time voice-to-MIDI interface)

• Audio application: C++ (VST, JUCE), JavaScript/TypeScript (Web Audio API)

# **EDUCATION**

EDUCATION	
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)  Ph.D. Candidate in Graduate School of Culture Technology  Music and Audio Computing Lab (Advisor: Juhan Nam)	2017 - 2024
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)  M.S. in Graduate School of Culture Technology  Music and Audio Computing Lab (Advisor: Juhan Nam)	2015 - 2017
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minored in Culture Technology)	2011 - 2015
EXPERIENCE	
AudAi, Republic of Korea Chief Technical Officer (CTO)	Jun 2023 - present
T-Brain, SK Telecom, Republic of Korea Research Intern (Topic: Piano transcription and chord recognition)	Aug 2019 - Feb 2020
Clova Multimedia, Naver Corp., Republic of Korea Research Intern (Topic: Musical instrument classification)	Jun 2018 - Sep 2018
Keio Media Design, Japan Student Researcher Visiting (Advisor: Liwei Chan) (Topic: UI/UX design for 3D touch)	Jan 2016 - Feb 2016
Seoul National University, Republic of Korea Undergraduate Research Program at MARG (Advisor: Kyogu Lee) (Topic: Visualizing audio compressor with VST)	Jul 2014 - Aug 2014
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Republic of Korea Undergraduate Research Program at AIM Lab. (Advisor: Woonseung Yeo)	Jan 2013 - Jun 2013

#### RESEARCH PROJECTS

## T-Brain X, SK Telecom

Jul. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Development of multi-singer synthesis and modification algorithm

# Ministry of Trade, Industry, and Energy

Jul. 2017 - Dec. 2020

Development of conversational speech synthesis technology to express emotion and personality of robots through sound source diversification

# Korea Creative Content Agency (KOCCA)

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2018

Development of pattern, phrase, motif-based korean virtual instruments

## ADVISING & TEACHING ACTIVITY

- TA, GCT634 Musical applications of machine learning, KAIST (Mar 2019 Jun 2019)
- TA, GCT583 Museum technology in digital era, KAIST (Sep 2018 Dec 2018)
- Mentor, Research & education program, Korea science academy (Mar 2018 Dec 2018)
- TA, GCT674 Knowledge-based system design, KAIST (Sep 2017 Dec 2017)
- TA, CTP201 Introduction to culture technology, KAIST (Sep 2016 Dec 2016)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# A Real-Time Lyrics Alignment System Using Chroma and Phonetic Features for Classical Vocal Performance

Jiyun Park, **Sangeon Yong**, Taegyun Kwon, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2024 (accepted)

# A Phoneme-Informed Neural Network Model for Note-Level Singing Transcription

Sangeon Yong, Li Su, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2023

## Neural Vocoder Feature Estimation for Dry Singing Voice Separation

Jaekwon Im, Soonbeom Choi, **Sangeon Yong**, Juhan Nam

Procs. of the 14th Asia Pacific Signal and Information Processing Association Annual Summit and Conference (APSIPA), 2022

#### Children's Song Dataset for Singing Voice Research

Soonbeom Choi, Wonil Kim, Saebyul Park, Sangeon Yong, Juhan Nam

Late Breaking Demo in the 21st International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR), 2020

# PyTSMod: A Python Implementation of Time-Scale Modification Algorithms

Sangeon Yong, Soonbeom Choi, Juhan Nam

Late Breaking Demo in the 21st International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR), 2020

## Korean Singing Voice Synthesis Based on Auto-Regressive Boundary Equilibrium GAN

Soonbeom Choi, Wonil Kim, Saebyul Park, Sangeon Yong, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2020

# Data Augmentation and Model Optimization for Piano Transcription

Sangeon Yong, Changhyun Kim, Jiwon Kim

Music Information Retrieval Evaluation eXchange (MIREX) in the 20th ISMIR, 2019

# Use the Force: Incorporating Touch Force Sensors into Mobile Music Interaction

Edward Jangwon Lee, Sangeon Yong, Soonbeom Choi, Roshan Peiris, Liwei Chan, Juhan Nam

Lecture Notes in Computer Science (revised selected papers of CMMR 2017), Vol. 11265, 2018

# Singing Expression Transfer from One Voice to Another for a Given Song

Sangeon Yong, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2018

## Use the Force: Incorporating Touch Force Sensors into Mobile Music Interaction

Edward Jangwon Lee, Sangeon Yong, Soonbeom Choi, Roshan Peiris, Liwei Chan, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the 13th International Symposium on Computer Music Multidisciplinary Research (CMMR), 2017

# ForceClicks: Enabling Efficient Button Interaction with Single Finger Touch

Sangeon Yong, Edward Jangwon Lee, Roshan Peiris, Liwei Chan, Juhan Nam

Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction (TEI), 2017

# DOMESTIC PUBLICATIONS

# 가창 음원의 음악적 표현 이식 시스템

Sangeon Yong, Juhan Nam

한국 음성 학회, 2019

# **THESIS**

# Transferring Singing Expressions from One Voice to Another Sangeon Yong

M.S. thesis, Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, 2017

## **PATENTS**

# Singing Expression Transfer System

Juhan Nam, Sangeon Yong

US Patent Grant, 10885894, 2021

# Singing Voice Expression Transfer System

Juhan Nam, Sangeon Yong

Korea Patent Grant, 10-1925217, 2018

## **AWARDS**

- Korean society of speech sciences (KSSS) spring conference best paper award (2019)
- KAIST spring semester URP program second prize (2013)